I'm Scott. I'm Russell. And I'm Leo. This is Spitball.
Welcome to Spitball, where three solution seekers and a guest empty their heads of startup and tech product ideas that they have stuck up in there so you can all have them for free.
Anything that we say is yours to keep. And Russell, you brought our guest this week, right?
I did. I brought the incredible Kayla. She's doing amazing stuff with people. She helps people any way she can. I'm going to keep it at that.
Wow.
That's a way of saying you have no idea what I do.
She's nice. She's fun. She's cool.
She gets people out of bad situations. We'll say that.
We're so excited to have Kayla here.
Batman?
I just don't want, I don't want, you know, because I don't want people like finding Kayla and start talking to her too much, you know, because she's a valuable person that doesn't need to be hounded on because of our mass fanhood.
Right.
Keeping you anonymous.
You ready for your profile to get the Spitball bump where you're about to go viral?
That's it.
It's happening.
You're going to get hundreds of thousands of followers because she's on Spitball.
Kayla, we're super excited to have you here.
Kayla has told us that before the show that she's brought us a dating idea, which is exciting because we've had dating ideas in the docket ready to go, Scott and I, so that we could do what we've wanted to do for a long time, which is tonight we are doing Oops! All Love Corners.
Each of us, including the game, will have some Russell's Love Corner to share.
So to get us started, we're going to be playing Tinder or Timber.
I want to raid for you an actual dating app and when it was founded, a little bit about it.
I want you to tell me if it's still around or not.
This is a list of really weird ones.
And of course, we got to start every week as we do with our guest, Kayla.
I want to tell you about Bristler, B-R-I-S-T-L-R.
This was a real thing started in 2014, which connects people with beards and those who
love beards.
Users sign up, create profiles, find matches based off of beard preferences.
The platform served its niche community.
But is it still around?
I kind of hope not.
So I'm going to go with no.
2014, it's still around today.
You too could be finding the bearded man of your dreams or be the bearded man of somebody else's if you go to Bristler.
Scott, I want to tell you about Hater.
Hater was on Shark Tank.
Hater matched people based off of mutual dislikes.
It offered a unique way to find compatibility through shared hatreds.
It was founded in 2017, but is it still around?
2017?
Yeah, I'd say that's still around then.
They shut down shortly after Shark Tank.
can't imagine why okay hold on i think it should open back up especially the kendrick lamar drake
everyone's becoming a hater it's literally my dating
you gotta find an alt buddy that's hilarious let's try
i was gonna call it red flags man i had a great idea all right you know what i'll pivot a little
bit off of that that's so good i'm keeping that in russell let me tell you about an app that was
founded or a website back way back in 2007 it's called sea captain date sea captain date connects
sea captains with those who love the ocean providing a platform of nautical themed romance
here's the best tagline of the night users who join can quote find their first mate oh are they
still around or did they retire? This was back in 2007 that they started. They have to be around.
It's like sugar daddy app, but less direct, you know? Boat season. Boat season. They are still
around. See Captain Date. Very good. Of course it would be zero all except for Russell, the expert
of the love corner who's got his first point on the board. Next time through. Kayla, I want to
tell you about sizzle s-i-z-z-l this is a dating app created by oscar meyer for bacon lovers sizzle
allows you to connect over your mutual love of meats it was created as a fun and quirky like
marketing stunt in 2015 but is it still around no it's still around that is wrong i know you
could sign up for sizzle today isn't that bizarre yeah over meat meat lover 26 or something they've
expanded it to be more like you know let me share a little bit about my uh my smoker you know food
that i made and stuff but uh yeah as far as i could tell there is still a site called sizzle
that seems to be squatting on the domain who's doing something over there so i think there's
still a thing that gave me the ick for sure all right scott i want to tell you about all one word
herp date h-e-r-p capital date herp date provides a platform for hsv positive singles to meet and
date if you've got you know the clap it features tools for connecting and supporting individuals
with herpes and started at least in the early 2000s but is it still around early 2000s like
pre-smartphone yeah as a website herp date yeah why not that's that's still going live right is
indeed still around you too could hang out on herp date the hottest spot on the internet can we talk
about this for a second because like go for it oh my gosh it's like oh i guess that kind of sucks so
like there's like a part of me that's like oh good for you you know you find people but also it's
just like holy cow herpes at least at least they stopped spreading it yeah keep them in their own
little community i guess like a leper colony an online commune for herpes russell i gotta tell
you about two words awake dating awake dating catered to people who are interested in conspiracy
theories allowing them to have a platform for truthers to connect with each other it allows
users to find like-minded individuals who share their interests in alternative viewpoints and
theories founded in 2016 is it still around today awake dating there must be it's gotta be there's
too many crazy people it's still around yes sir something weird about 2016 i wonder why that was
founded then keeping them all together in the same spot like keeping them breathing in the same like
a leper colony all right all right kayla kayla i gotta tell you about vampire passions vampire
passions, two words spelled as it sounds, catered to vampires and vampire enthusiasts,
which is a bizarre way to say that.
Offering communication options for chats and message boards, you can connect over shared
interests in vampire-related books, movies, and lifestyles.
Since the early 2000s, it was founded, but is it still around?
Early 2000s?
Yeah, I think so.
Early 2000s.
I feel like I've heard of this.
I think it's still around.
It is still around.
Why have you heard of this?
Not traditionally a dating app specifically, but it's got a thing.
Dude, I have no idea I've heard this, but there's a community.
They're out there.
You're making it sound like you're trying to say that you're not a part of it.
There are dozens of us.
No, you are.
Russell, I don't need to say I'm not a part of it because it's very clear that I'm not a part of it.
I don't know what.
I like that it has both vampire enthusiasts and vampires.
That's pretty great.
Scott, I got to tell you about Gluten-Free Singles, which provided a platform for individuals with celiac disease and gluten intolerances to meet.
connect it offers resources community features and a supportive environment for gluten-free
singles specifically founded in 2013 best domain name ever and absolutely that must still be it's
still around yeah yes sir they've got a whole dating advice column and everything growing in
numbers ever since 2013 that's right last time here's uh russell last one salad match all one
word developed by the just salad company salad match brought back the communal experience of
The Big Bowl of Salad.
The app connected people who hit it off while waiting in line at their restaurant.
This was a restaurant that saw people hitting it off and said, we got to make a dating app around this.
I guess you make connections off of shared love of salad bars.
I don't totally get it.
Founded in 2012.
Is it still around?
No, it's not.
I can't.
Please.
No, it is not.
Very good.
No, it's not.
Which I think is because you got all three right.
You got awake dating.
So, yeah, you got all three.
Well done, Russell.
Of course.
Our local Love Corner expert.
I mean, who's bonding over salad?
Like, if you're on that app, I feel like everybody found each other and then that was it.
That was the only people on the planet.
Rabbits love it.
I define myself by my salad enthusiasm.
You won.
That means I think you got to go first this week.
What do you got for us this week, Russlin?
Okay.
Well, as you guys already know, my original idea was kind of taken.
Hater.
Okay.
by some shark tank people so i have two ideas now i don't know which one to go with all right
we're gonna put this as part of it i like this idea of the way to a man's heart is through his
stomach so taking a spin off of sizzle and then i also have red flags where you talk about red flags
and you bring up your red flags and if you don't you know i'm gonna go with red flags that's the
one i'm gonna go with go with red flags because mine's kind of sort of a little bit like what
you're talking about all right so here's the dating app idea if you can't have me at my worst
you can't have me at my best all right so the dating app is all about showing off your red flags
right telling people what makes you different and unique and is a common red flag okay or uncommon
keep you spicy keep you different and you're matching people based on their red flags not on
they're green ones sure show them at your worst okay uh that's it what are some examples of like
are you talking about like deep dark dirty uh this is a disgusting fact about me kind of stuff or like
where's the threshold that's tough i have trouble when they say all right we're gonna play two truths
and a lie like i don't know what to say about myself so like if i was presented with a text
box on an app that said what what are some of your red flags i don't know if i could that would
be a tough one i think it is tough i think it's important to figure out what makes you a red flag
what's your red flags do you guys know what your red flags are i'm sure people could tell me there
it is so that's where you bring that's the viral component so instead of you should i got it i got
it you have your exes get sent to form then fill out the flags about you like you're getting endorsed
on linkedin god and you can't see the answers and then you just get blindly matched with someone
else yeah whoa you have been endorsed three times for talks over people are people out there like
vouching for their exes you know what i mean like all right you know we're breaking up i'll i'll set
up your profile like i know we're breaking up right now but like if you set up your red flags
yeah it might need to be a long time ago but i mean it would be fun to get your friends to show
like so do your red flags maybe maybe friends maybe not exes oh that'd be tough though like
i mean you could do the opposite you could do both red and green flags right so it's like the
roses and thorns you know here are your thorns here are the roses and you have your friends
fill that out for you or yourself right one good one bad what about like your beige flags where
it's like you don't know whether it's a red or green yeah you're right some people might see a
red flag is a green flag you know yeah or beige are there certain red flags okay kayla because
you're the resident single person right now are there red flags that you're like that ain't a red
flag that's a green one for me do you know what i mean no i want like i want examples so um guys
big into uh let's say crypto left that's a good or left i don't know like like uh like fast cars
like they're beat like deep in that fast car game you know it's like is that or is that like a beige
flag you know what i mean like some people might be like oh i love the fast cars yeah that's a hold
up bass that they've caught on their left left hard left with really sharp angular sunglasses
and backwards hat but do you know of a girl that would be interested in that like oh yeah i mean
like yeah like the fishing thing like country girls would be interested in that for sure
there's probably some overlap there of your red flags my green yeah or like yeah going with the
fast cars one i think i don't think it's a green flag but like a guy with a motorcycle is pretty
like that seems fun for a moment and some people might see that as red probably not long run yeah
yeah that's a good example a guy with a lot of tattoos some people are really into that green
oh yeah the pete davidson's of the world have been making it all right oh sorry the the mgk's the
justin peepers davidson uh yeah just stop you're behind yeah right i don't know why but everybody
who's timothy chalamet is where it's at now right not for me oh he looks like a pre-bubescent boy
i feel like after a while when you finally get your head wrapped or you get the algorithm fed
with the things that you find as red or green flags there's got to be some data science in
there that says if people like these three things then these five other things might trend toward
good or bad too right how do you it's like a flag sorting algorithm that you're looking to make
So you're saying like, I sign up for this dating app and I straight up put in, it gives you a list of like a hundred different things.
Like you said, tattoos, fast cars, pictures with bass in them.
And I just straight up have my dropdown and say red, green, or beige on it.
And I put that for all of them and that essentially creates my algorithm in the back.
And then that'll match me with...
Do apps have something like this already?
It's all about likes at this point.
Like what is the profile creation process like nowadays?
Okay, I think you guys were saying this.
What if you didn't, you had other people,
instead of them swiping left and just moving on,
they have to label what made them not like it.
And now your red flags are not generated by you,
but by the other people.
Plus you get anonymous feedback afterwards of like,
this is what's wrong with your profile.
Maybe you should update this.
Or hey, the second picture really turned off a lot of people for some reason.
Or this is what's wrong with your personality.
Maybe change that.
When you unfriend someone or block someone, you have to put a reason why.
That's it.
So when you're unmatching somebody, in order to do that, you must leave feedback.
Or swipe left, like Kayla said.
Yes.
That's really interesting.
And then once a month, you see all the people that you swiped right on.
And the ones that you liked and they didn't like, they tell you why.
Oh, my god.
You better have high self-esteem for that.
Yeah. It is trial by fire. It feels like you're creating like a genetic algorithm where you've got like the best of the you're creating the best profiles that the group consensus can make for each person. Then you can take that. But maybe the end goal is this is now created the perfect profile that you then take to the other side.
It's about putting your best foot forward, okay?
You know?
Just because you take, you know, maybe you're better on your right side than your left,
and you believed your, you know, right side was your better side.
That's what this app is about.
Could we pivot this app to not be a dating service, but a profile creation system?
Yeah.
Where it's a peer-to-peer review of all the photos and bios and stuff you're writing?
So there's subreddits dedicated to this.
Like, rate my profile and stuff.
And people just post and be like, what do you think of this?
And people will give hard, honest criticism of it.
Like roast me.
It's not, it's weirdly wholesome.
Like they're legitimately trying to help you
and not just crush your self-esteem,
but they're also brutally honest at the same time.
Yeah, don't tell Russell that
because he'll jump on that subreddit
and crush everyone's self-esteem.
I can see him thinking right now.
Yeah, he's like, let me troll after this.
Hey, idiot, you need more bass.
This should be a fiver service.
This has to exist, right?
The profile glow up.
That's a small ass fish.
you know what they say about small fish the best you got i think that's cool like the negative
rating system or like the you know because i feel like people like girls swipe right or the other
way is right the one you like left is bad when making all the data naps i don't i've never like
used it i've only used them when like kayla's over or something i don't have when sarah's over
yeah sorry sarah that's right oh sorry sarah um yeah it's left then like then it's like instead
of you accumulating points you're actually putting into the system and getting people more matches
and maybe how's this too it connects to other dating apps and so now your profile that you're
making and updating connects to all the dating apps in the system bubble bubble tinder all the
ones that i know tweezer gabhart the clap one i make dating apps i don't know them
herp day there it is see captain day sizzle vampire passion yes how big is your fish
it's a pretty small fish that's a northern pike baby oh light him up there should be a dude man
a dude app of just like dudes rating each other's fish catches just big ass fish oh that would
probably be so popular fish tinder finder just like people browsing big ass fish you know but
i did tell okay like for the viewers at home all the women that listen to this show okay dudes have
very few photos of themselves and the one time their bros take a photo of them is when they're
holding up a fish.
This is the only reason why
they have photos all the time on there.
Because there's no other time. That's a good picture of me.
I think I could get another 12 years out of this.
When are bros taking pictures of bros?
You know? Like, oh,
here's a photo. I'm going to take a snap, a picture
of Leo just standing
in front of a flag, looking cool.
I don't know.
Like a fish. Well, why can't they just take
the picture before they catch the fish?
Like, you're on a boat. Show that off.
Yeah, share your cool boat.
Leave the fish in the lake.
Bro, why were you taking a photo of me?
Like, I haven't even caught a fish yet.
Like, that's so weird.
That is the, that's so weird.
That's how it goes, Kayla.
That's the conversation.
I mean, and also, like, they're on a boat, so they're bending over, and their shirts are up, and their butt crack's showing.
Oh, my God.
I'll put that as beige flag.
It's a B.
Prefers to show ass crack.
Beige flag.
Your worst photos, just.
Now that's interesting.
I wonder if you could troll the Google Photos API or whatever
and pull out bad, unflattering pictures to go with your red flag thing.
If you're going to make a site about all your flaws,
it doesn't seem right to have a beautiful headshot.
You've got to have a picture of you mid-sneeze.
Just give it a link to your Google Photos and be like,
pick the worst pictures of me.
You have no control over it.
Uneditable, exactly.
That's tough.
Here's 10.
Pick your worst five.
That would be.
That's tough.
I feel like at that point, nobody's going to sweat.
Everybody leaves.
Who wants to just go on that to literally be bullied?
Yeah, that's probably true.
Why would you want to match with people at their worst?
Still better than the salad one.
All right, Leo, what do you got this week?
Okay.
Name is TBD here.
but my love corner for today is re-eating meat.
You note what leftovers you have in your fridge.
What did I cook this week?
I have no idea where this is going.
Other people have done the same,
and it uses cooking blogs and New York Times cooking recipes and stuff
to decide what you guys could make together.
If I have leftover chicken that I made on the grill last night,
and you've got tortillas that are going to go bad,
we could get together and talk over making quesadillas. Reheat and meat. That's incredible.
I really like making all this food, but I have some leftover. I wish I had someone to share it
with. You get a natural selection of people who like home cooking. So you're not just going to
a movie or whatever. And you can share that passion and get good meals from each other.
That's a first date built into the app.
Can I go on there if I have nothing in my fridge and I just need my next meal?
You just want the equivalent of couch surfing.
I want to eat a stranger's leftovers.
With them.
Swipe right.
And you're swiping right on both their meal proposal for the week and them.
As a person, of course.
Ooh, you got to show off.
I make fancy leftovers.
I have a seafood allergy, so I never see that dish that you have slash you as a person.
Is there anything here?
I'm trying to spit it so it's not just food.
But I think there's something related to bringing people together over mutual needs, we'll say.
Mutual needs.
It's every dating app.
I have needs.
Needs.
Needs may not be the right word there.
I hunger.
Air, leftover, sex, you know.
Like, I'll bring the drinks, you bring the food.
Sure, sure, sure.
Like, or like...
Ooh, like a wine pairing for it.
I propose a meal and you have to bring a fancy wine or something.
Exactly.
Or a cocktail.
Yes.
Coffee and donuts, you know?
Totally.
Bread, lunch meat.
So you're going to this app with some interests and things you are and are not looking for
and personality things that matter to you and all that stuff, minimum.
But you're also going with your dietary preferences.
And it's matching on both of those things.
If you end up with this person long term, you're going to be eating a lot of meals together.
Maybe it's good to get on the same page about what you like from the get go, huh?
Yes.
You could turn this into like you partner with all these cooking places like a spice shop, you know?
Sure.
Like, hey, you bring something, I bring something, you know, or like, what is it?
The paint and pour kind of maybe mentality.
You go there, you're going to bring something.
I'm going to bring something and it'd be some talking point, right?
Yeah.
And then you're at this date at the cooking place.
So they got the spice.
They're selling you all that shit.
But then they stuff.
Learn how to do hibachi, but bring your own stuff, your raw ingredients that are going to go bad in two days.
Well, that's like a great dating app, a dating idea.
Like, I would love to, like, learn hibachi.
Yeah.
Get me and my wife there.
bocce meetup you bring you bring the eggs i bring the rice just yeah we'll provide the oil and the
lighter have a good time making a volcano together you know i think a lot of there's
gonna be a definitely there's gonna definitely be a specific type of person that would be like
this is my app like like i've been waiting figuring out ways to get rid of this food
there's a lot of foodies out there yeah yeah i don't think it's just a utilitarian thing to get
rid of your leftovers but maybe that's part of the the appeal i guess sure what what if it was
more like that like i'm gonna cook a really good meal and you're gonna cook a really good meal and
we'll do like a meal exchange right it's gonna be leftovers there we go you know it's a flex
weird flex bro right like how good are you at cooking all right bring your a game yeah you're
showing off that's right you know okay that's where the reheat i keep i love the name reheating
meat do you the the whole leftovers thing is still like what's throwing me off but like no
i make my fancy meal heat and meat and we both no reheat bring it somewhere and we eat it oh my god
is that too far yikes no heat me no you're heating then me heating is different
or just call it i'm in heat i don't know no no okay i love this oh man yes but okay referring
to your walk and your grill where what are you thinking of oh that's right anyways scott scott
yes like flex your cooking skills meet up right this goes to my um throwback to uh byom bring me
your own meats okay you set up hot grills all over you know you go to byo byom place you cook
your food at that kitchen you know imagine hibachi places you throw your food on there and you're
meeting and you're talking and you're eating it together right boom absolutely kayla's like nope
this is definitely this is this is not the dating app for kayla but wait maybe i don't know what's
Don't speak for Caleb.
You're right.
What would be your weird...
Okay, everybody here on this call.
What's your weird flex meal?
Weird flex meal.
Yeah, what would be the meal?
We have a grill that does smoking, and we make a smoked pork tenderloin that's like
apple juice and thyme and stuff, and it's really easy to make, but it's amazing.
You get the smoke ring and everything in just a couple hours.
Ooh, I want to meet you.
Smoked pork tenderloin.
I want to meet you.
That sounds amazing.
What would you bring that's like a flex to this app?
I got pork chops that I marinated, and they're amazing.
People talk to me about it.
They are.
Nice.
A week.
I marinated them for like 24 hours, and they come out hell.
Awesome.
So good.
Some form of pie.
Oh, yes.
Italian, of course.
Red sauce going through.
Get that going ahead of time.
Let it sit for like three days, and then it's all perfect.
Dude, Scott, with your last name of Brandon Isio,
somebody swiped right on you and did not get an Italian meal,
I think that would have just been like a slap in the face.
Tacos? What the hell?
I'm bringing tacos. I make a great
coconut curry.
Alright, Kayla, what's your
weird flex meal? I guess I'd say
either soup. I'm really good at just throwing
together whatever I have into a good soup
or stir fry. Totally.
The stir fry would be so great.
Bring all your leftovers. I was just going to say, if only
I had a little bit of, oh, someone on
reheating me. It's got
exactly what I need to finish this stir fry off.
You're literally swiping based on
their ingredients they have available.
I mean, maybe they look interesting enough, but you never know.
It's so superficial to look at only the people.
Their pantry.
You gotta look.
As your unsolicited wingman, Kayla, you're gonna need to bring up like cookies, apple
pie, generational apple pie, all right?
That's gonna get any man on the app to swipe on that.
Yeah.
That doesn't sound like my type.
Apple pie sounds like a southerner that we do not have the same views.
See?
Okay, so this is really a real match then, right?
Your meal.
I ain't going to match with an apple pie person.
Like, dudes are always going to be cooking meats.
Unless you're Italian.
You're cooking pasta, right?
I like a good breakfast pizza.
This is rough.
Oh, no.
So good.
Oh, yeah, that's probably sacrilege to the Italian.
My bad.
My me.
That's right.
I'm trying to think of, like, unique, weird stuff that would make you stand out on the app.
Dude, this is better.
Sizzle needs to take this idea, Leo.
The Oscar Mayer app.
Yeah.
sizzle you can have this for a nominal fee very reasonable licensing you can have it for free
that's the conceit of the show all right scott i'm ready to enter scott's love corner what do
you got for me all right i like hardware and i want to do a love corner that's based on hardware
so you guys ever you ever heard of orange theory it's like a weird culty uh fitness group where
you go it's expensive and you go and they give you like a heartbeat monitor and then they display
everyone's heartbeat monitor up on a screen up there and everyone's working out and the whole
thing is like work as hard as you want but try to keep your heartbeat within such a range and like
interesting concept i want to do that with dating i want to make like a chemistry checking wristband
or wearable device that'll analyze like the subtle biological signals and give a compatibility score
either of yourself or something that can check for like skin temp or analyze pupil dilation or
even like pheromones are coming off of you at that point and then you get actual analytics at the end
of that yeah like whoa am i attracted this person or not and then you could have so many different
variations of that like you could have a whole like orange theory you do speed dating where
everyone has one of these bands on there and you get actual numbers by the end of like oh this
person was talking to this person and these what their levels were going or you just use it for
yourself and on a date and you can get your feeling but you can also get the metrics afterwards and
be like was i actually into that or not this is getting really dystopian really quick but they
usually do so like getting your score at the end of go-karting like oh i matched best with numbers
three and eleven okay interesting it sounds like gattaca or something like you know what i mean a
A lot of these turn into Gattaca by the end.
Okay, so I'm trying to think.
So this is like biology matching.
You're still going out on normal dates and other things.
But I feel like this is like a thing.
Like types?
I guess it's like where you find your type, right?
I don't even know if it's types.
It's like your bodily reaction.
Yes, thank you.
Thank you.
I think it's interesting.
I think it'd be interesting to see those results after a date.
I don't know because I feel like if I went on a first date,
I feel like I black out a little bit afterwards.
It'd be nice to see the metrics of like, oh, okay.
My heart was like, it increased at certain points.
So it seemed like there was some sort of reaction there.
You're watching your heart rate at that.
You're watching your skin temp.
You're watching all these things.
You go on 10 dates.
It was like stable.
Yeah.
Maybe I was just so bored during the whole thing.
Oh, this is while you're on the date.
Yeah.
Do not listen.
I missed that part.
I'm curious to hear what you were thinking on this one.
I literally thought you were just wearing this monitor all day.
and then you were just like, alright,
it's gonna match you with random people.
No, no, no, you are
on a date at this point and you
are recording the whole,
data logging the whole time. It's quantifying speed
data, you dork. Okay, I don't
know where I was gonna Spitball with this
because I was like, I was like, holy
cow. That's tough.
You guys are killing me.
I was so confused.
Tell us more about the random lady at the bank.
I can stop sweating.
please can i add something to this all right so it is also recording and transcribing so that you
get the topics and cadences and things like that that you are interested in to try to put okay
numbers around that i need a second that would be kind of that would be interesting to have a whole
transcript of your date because kayla you were talking about i you know i kind of black out
during that like so if my heart rate peaked at 631 like what was even happening during that point of
the date hmm where we was there something that was like triggering that how do you how do you
capture the thing that's actually the moment maybe instead of transcripting the whole day it does
snapshots of like when there's like some sort of oh an event or shift your heart rate spiked at
this point i don't think totally yeah i don't think i want to see the whole transcripts then
you're going to go back and be like why did i ever say that at the same time though i would
I absolutely love to know what the first date was, like what we talked about and whatnot, like with my with my wife right now.
Like, what was our first date going through?
Would you have used a device to quantify and speed date?
I mean, I don't even know when Carrie and I's first date was.
Like, not.
We were like friends.
Oh, that's a good point.
You guys have been dating a long time.
I got out of the friend zone, y'all, though.
So, like.
There's hope for you yet.
Because that's who's watching or listening to our show right now.
But I think that is like super cool because it would be just like you can see let's say you have like three first dates and you could look at your metrics and you could be like, wow, I think I actually really like that person.
I can see my metrics do this, but like this person I'm not sure of.
And I can tell literally because of my biology, like my physiology during that date.
Like, hmm.
I think the magic in this is the algorithm knows all of the metrics for everybody.
So if it sees this person was really interested in the other one, was it?
It doesn't show anyone.
it's only hey sorry thanks for coming you didn't really get any good matches this one or actually
there was something back and you have compatibility on both sides at the end of the night it only
shows when there's a match you know yeah and maybe even like let's say the other side of the date
wasn't having a great time maybe you just gotta but you did like maybe you gotta like your follow-up
game's gotta be fire yeah like it generates the points that the other person was most interested
and all that stuff and it only sends the other party each other's data this person was super
interested when you talked about this thing this person was less interested when you reached over
and touched their hand or whatever it was it's giving you the feedback from their wristband and
vice versa how do you make yourself a better person to date that's a whole nother app in itself
i know i was just thinking that too yeah that's rough we're back to the last one with the um the
app to make your profile better i guess this is the first hardware accessory from that company
could you apply that to anything else besides first dates like i feel like that's just like
interesting like interviews i i mean i know this is the love corner episode but i feel like that's
really cool for like interviews and other aspects of life so that way you don't just buy it for
dating you can use it for other things what excites you in general you tend to be stressed
out when people talk about this general yeah yeah you're you're one-on-one with this guy
every Tuesday at like three, you're like, oh God.
It's taking years off your life, man.
Straight up.
It goes better when you avoid these topics, right?
Yeah.
I think we talked a little bit about this,
but Amazon tried something kind of like this
with the Amazon Halo.
It was a Fitbit-like tracker,
but it would say things like,
hey, you sounded like you were using an angry tone there.
Maybe tone it down kind of stuff
to like give you a little bit of feedback about yourself.
It was very quickly discontinued.
People did not like that.
The robots telling me to be nicer.
uh nope that goes to the trash so you gotta go to the warehouse the dump where all those are
sitting unused and buy them and flash your firmware on there that's sending all of its
data to the centralized speed dating service this wouldn't be hard hardware to make all the sensors
are already out there heart rate throw it on the apple watch bang make an app of thermistors yeah
that's what that's what i'm gonna say like sell it to apple boom there you go put it on the app store
Or just make it an app with existing.
Everyone who goes to the event has to have one.
Or make a headband, you know?
So like when you're on your first date, you're wearing a giant red headband that's tracking.
Blinking lights.
Spinning thing on top.
Shooting sparks.
A Google car.
No one is allowed to be confident here.
I was really stressed out all night.
I wonder why my confidence wasn't high.
I had that ridiculous pinwheel hat on.
Yeah.
Can you quantify love?
That's a dumb question.
dumb way to ask that but like is this possible i guess there's like the stress response and stuff
when pheromone sniffer do humans put off much pheromones i don't know much about that i'm all
about trying to make technology to smell they were didn't ever talk about this the smell tech
there's a whole thing around that there's an industry around artificial noses to detect like
presence of chemicals and stuff in the air that's right ai will never beat our noses that's what
That's what it is, guys.
As long as we got our nose, AI will never take us over.
The only thing that we can't do better than chat GPT is smell the roses.
Collect that data.
That's poetry right there.
AI it, all right?
Smell this.
All right, Kayla, what love corner idea have you brought us this week?
Okay, so mine's a build off of Russell's friend of a friend idea, I think.
Episode two.
Classic.
So like that. Yeah. So backstory. I personally think ideally I'd meet someone through a mutual friend. And so there's also I've seen apps where the only way like certain people can get on the app because like dating now is just scary. There's like scary people out there. So the only way people can get on the apps is with endorsements. Like someone saying, oh, they're like a good person, blah, blah, blah, which I get. You can lie, whatever.
But I want to mix those two together.
And the app is you download either your contacts or your social media friends to the app.
And then you can see like their mutuals and see like who's out there like through your mutual friends.
And then if you like someone, your mutual, you can like hit them up through the app if they're on there or outside the app.
And like, see, do you think this is a match or something like that?
So like kind of get an endorsement with the mutual friend.
Just create LinkedIn dating.
I guess kind of.
Facebook announced Facebook dating a while back, and that was more or less their pitch.
They already know the social graph.
They know who's friends of friends of people and stuff.
Like, they can have a really good insight into that, and then it never really went anywhere.
And I always was perplexed by that.
It seems like a natural fit for Facebook or somebody else like that who's already built the who's connected with who stuff.
Do they do endorsements, though?
Like, I feel like somebody becomes more appealing.
Like somebody that like, wow, they have like 400 endorsements, but they look ugly AF.
But like, like maybe I should read their profile.
Like all of a sudden, right?
I just even mean like Russell, let's say you had a friend that I was like, oh, I find him cute.
And you're like, well, also, I think your personalities mesh.
Like I do think this is a good match.
Yes.
So you're starting by finding the people who are friends of friends.
And then before contact is initiated, you somehow get the friend who you are a friend of a friend through to like review that idea.
Yeah.
And I feel like that adds just like a safety layer for like.
That's awesome.
Oh, huge.
I would do that all day.
Yeah.
Approve.
Deny.
Yeah.
You definitely would.
But I also thought it's like it expands it because I feel like your friend group, like just like even in Holland, you have only so much so many friends in Holland.
Then I have friends in Chicago who know way more people than I would never meet normally in person.
This is a way to broaden it, but still within the friends.
Dude, you meet a friend and you're like, hey.
You have a friend that you haven't seen in a while.
It's like, do you want to just share your contacts with me real quick?
Or connect?
And then you can talk about also all their single friends.
When they start talking to you about all your single friends.
Like, oh, I know so many people that would love to date you.
And then you do the sync thing.
And now you're talking about all your friends together.
And now whether or not you like them or not, it's just a great conversation for friend groups to talk about all these single people.
And so the conversation is cool.
Yeah.
Or like, I don't think this person's good, but maybe this person's good.
Yes.
If I could install an app and every once in a while it gets a push notification that says, hey, your friend that you're close with wants to know what you think about this other friend.
Give commentary about that connection.
That would be so fun.
How well would these two go together?
I would call up both people and do the same thing.
Well, sometimes it's not a good match though, right?
Are you just blindly matching everybody who asks?
Russell would be like, yep, yep, yep, this is great.
Actually, now that I think about it, the single guys that I know and the single girls that I know, I'm like, why none of them are compatible with each other?
Yeah, okay, good.
I think it'd be cool to see like all the endorsements from all those people.
And like even like friends of friends could endorse like I met this guy one time or hell, even exes be like, I'm an ex.
I endorse this person.
There are some people that are very big advocates of their exes to go find their next person.
And that's a huge green flag.
Right.
Like and also the person that wants to see that person's ex is like all in.
Like, let me see that person and who they are.
Probably.
Right.
The fact that they're endorsing him is either as a red flag or a green flag.
So it's like.
Yeah, it's like a beige, you know?
It's a beige, for sure.
Yeah.
I've said this before in the show, Kayla,
but my very first date with my wife
was crashed by a mutual friend
that we just happened to both be walking
downtown on 8th Street,
and we both saw him.
We're like, hey, Carl.
She goes, hey, Carl.
We go, how do you know Carl?
And then Carl came and crashed with us at the date,
and it was awesome,
because he's like, I know this person.
He's great.
I know this person.
He's not a serial killer.
You guys are great for each other.
That was it.
There you go.
Real life endorsement stamped on our forehead.
Real life scenario of the app.
I want this one.
This is the one I want to exist.
This is so much easier.
This is like the easier version of friend of a friend.
This was built for you, Russell.
Right?
I think I built off of it a little bit.
It made it a little bit better.
Way better because mine was like pictures of your friends.
I don't know.
It just felt.
Yeah, yours was like kind of weird.
Yours was just truly pimping people out.
And I don't think you were going to ever find someone to match.
That's why I didn't ever do it.
It just felt a little awkward at that point.
You know?
Sure.
This is way easier.
Also, you did it on Facebook.
You did a Facebook group, just posting your friends' pictures.
Please snatch this one up.
Porch pickup or delivery.
Oh my God.
Listen, that's so true.
It's like Facebook Marketplace, but for your single friends.
Oh boy.
Oh.
Yeah.
That's funny.
It was.
That's definitely where it went.
And how did it go?
It didn't go.
Nowhere, because it just felt wrong.
After you build the Facebook group and you try to invite people to it, you're like, is this a swinger group?
At first glance.
Come look at the menu.
Yeah, come look.
But you know what?
These women are yours for the taking.
It gets really weird when you're a married dude and you're trying to take pictures with your single friends.
I'm like, you know what?
This ain't for me.
The vibes were not right.
The intention nice, vibes bad.
Just so bad.
Did it get big?
No, I did not invite anybody because I'm like, this turns weird quick.
Sure.
But I like this endorsement.
Yeah, because each person coming to this theoretical app, Friend of a Friend 2.0,
they're coming to it consensually.
They're wanting to be there.
This is something that they haven't been put up to.
And then they're seeking the endorsements of their friend, Gref.
If you specify in the app you are interested in this gender, is that the only gender that's allowed to comment on and endorse?
Oh, otherwise it's just a bunch of wingmen.
Seeking women only.
So only women are allowed to say.
Right.
That's what I'm worried about.
I don't think so.
Is you have these 10 bros who are all endorsing each other.
No?
But that's like, yeah, that's on you to take that as a grain of salt if it's all the guy friends or not.
Can you tell? I guess, yeah, it's a UI problem at that point.
Yeah.
In your app, make sure it's obvious.
Kevin and Mike have only ever endorsed each other.
Yeah. I think it should say who endorsed you, so you can be like,
oh, okay, let me hit that person up and learn more if I need to learn more.
Yeah. Or like, what if you showed the relationship so it's like,
oh, his mom, his sister, his mom says he's a special little boy.
He's a nice young man.
i like the idea that you can't directly contact the other party until at least x percent of all
of the mutual friends between the two of you on the graph have signed off on it that's fun
oh that's interesting there's a bunch of people that you could swipe right on okay great now who
are out of these four people who know that person what are the two that you want to ask for their
blessing you know but maybe like that just motivates them to see each other maybe that's it
You know how like, okay, this is a pivot.
The parents when like, no, you're never allowed to see that boy ever again.
And it just makes the girl just like, no, I'm doing this to spite you.
My friend says that I always date trash men and she keeps rejecting them in the app.
But that just makes me want to.
Yeah, they've got Brita syndrome community.
Yes.
All right, Kayla, would you sign up for your own app?
Yeah, potentially, I guess.
What's the name of it?
I don't have a name.
I have no name for it.
It's just going to be bought by LinkedIn in the first year.
Endorsement of friends.
Dude, you know what's interesting is maybe I'd make more friends or try to get their contact,
like my casual acquaintances' contact information more often because I'm like,
oh, I need to get this on my profile for my friends.
My mutual friend connect, right?
Mutually assured connection.
That's the name of the app, MAC.
too long needs to be more web 2.0 it can just be like mutuals or like something mutuals yeah i do
think it gets very viral very quick quickly though because like your mutuals like it just
everybody wants to download it to share to their other friend and their other friend it just
quickly catches all of the people that could use this app there's a way bigger market than just
people who are single and looking for love you could have the like i could have this app and be
approving all the connections for others.
And that would be just as fun or more so.
Well,
keep a lookout for any of us on friend of a friend 2.0.
We'd be happy to approve your connections just because you're a listener.
Thank you very much for listening.
We hope you enjoyed yourself tonight.
And thank you so much,
Kayla.
That was great.
Thanks.
Our website is Spitball.show.
There you can find links to our YouTube channel,
other social media,
email us feedback,
comments,
ideas,
podcasts,
Spitball.show.
That's also how you can follow us on the Fediverse,
such as Mastodon.
We are podcast@spitball.show.
Our subreddit is r slash Spitball show.
Our intro/outro music is swingers by bonkers beat club.
If you wouldn't mind, if you did enjoy this show, we'd love to get a review or at least a subscribe, a follow on Apple podcast, Spotify, whatever you're listening on.
Review, add wherever you get your podcasts.
It's the best way for people to find out about the show.
New episodes coming out in two weeks.
We will see you then for the hundredth idea spectacular.
there.